[Music]
Hello and welcome to the 28th edition of Random Pursuit on the Incomparable Networks Game Show,
recorded in person at an undisclosed location.
Random Pursuit, a game that discards the board and shuffles trivia cards from lots and lots of trivia games.
I'm your scorekeeper, Stephen Chepanski, and now your host of this and every episode of Random Pursuit,
Erica Ensign. Thank you, Stephen. As always, we have a lovely group of players and I will introduce
them in the order in which they will play. That order was, as always, determined by Random.org.
That's its theme song. All right, every recording of this show needs to now be in person because
that was amazing. Is that its theme song part of the theme song? Yes. All right, so our first player
- Our first player, and we're going around the table,
this is delightful for me.
Our first player is a trivia stalwart
who has had a run of bad luck
with so many Doctor Who questions.
I have let him cut the deck
in hopes that his luck will change.
Welcome, Monty Ashley.
- I'm a stalwart.
- Our second player appears on, at most,
one incomparable podcast a year,
and we are glad it is this one.
Please welcome Lauren Snell.
- Hi there.
- Our third player is an author and podcaster
whose next book, "All Souls Lost"
is coming out October 17th
and is available for pre-order now.
Dan Moran.
- I wish somebody had told me.
Well, now I know, I guess.
It's so nice to be here as always.
- Our fourth player is appearing
on his first ever podcast on the Incarnable Network.
(all laughing)
Introducing Jason Snell.
- Hello, everybody.
I hope I do okay.
- And fifth, but never least,
the host of "Lion's Tower" and "Shields",
it's Shelly Brisbane.
Will there be questions about lions?
'Cause I expect questions about lions.
- Here's how it works.
Random pursuit is a lot like the classic
trivial pursuit board game,
but instead of using the board,
each player has their own six sided die
or dice rolling app like Dice by P-Calc.
Here we're around a table.
We have a lot of physical dice.
It's great.
- Sorry, James.
- It's just like P-Calc is last year's news.
- The players roll their die to determine
which question on the card they will answer.
I lost my place.
It's going great.
Do you have an editor?
I don't know.
No, I don't know.
For each question they answer correctly, they'll get one point.
If they answer correctly, they can roll again for another question, but they can also answer
up to three questions on each turn, except for the final round when there is no question
limit.
A crazy round.
If they roll the same number two times in a row on the same turn, they get to pick which
edition the question comes from.
The players usually have a list.
Today they don't.
Sorry.
It's way too long to read on the podcast.
It's way too long for them to read anyway, so it doesn't matter.
If they happen to roll the same number all three times on the same turn, they can pick
both the addition and the category.
And sometimes I don't notice this when it happens, so please holler if I miss it.
We will play for an amount of time determined by me, and then we'll do one last round with
no question limit, and the player with the highest score at the end becomes the random
champion with bragging rights that last until the next time we're all in person together
- At an un-disclosed location.
- Steaks.
- All right, is everybody ready?
- Yes.
- All right, Monty, you get to start us off.
Please roll your D six.
- Three.
- All right, this is coming from, and you cut the deck,
so you have only yourself to blame.
Chex TV trivia.
- Nice.
- Remember, these cards were from 1984.
The third question on the card is,
Yogi Bear first appeared on what cartoon show?
- Wow.
(all laughing)
That's an interesting question.
I'm going to say the Yogi Bear Show.
- I'm afraid that is not correct.
- Weird.
- Is that Hanna-Barbera hour or something?
- The Huckleberry Hound Show.
- Oh, okay.
- Was there like a backdoor pilot for Yogi Bear?
Yogi Bear?
(all laughing)
- That's a different question.
- If you see a backdoor pilot,
- I'm not going through it.
(all laughing)
- That's it, Dan's cleaning up his own mistakes.
I love it.
- All right, well, good try, Monty.
Now we're on to Lauren.
Go ahead and roll.
- Five.
- All right, this is coming from the Star Wars
Tribute Pursuit Edition,
in which category five is droids, creatures, and aliens.
This is a card that has a picture on one side.
And since we're in person,
I can actually show you the picture.
Usually it's not helpful at all, but here's the picture.
Go ahead and describe that if you can.
Just don't look at the other side of the card
or that would be cheating.
Maybe, who's that?
- I can't tell the emperor.
- I think it's the emperor and I think he's sitting
by the big round window thing in a throne.
- Yeah. - All right, well.
- I mean, technically anywhere the emperor sits
is a throne, I think.
That's how that works, right?
- Let's see if that picture helps you.
Who warned Luke not to underestimate the emperor?
- I think this picture is not helpful.
- That seems not helpful.
Well, I have no memory of that happening,
but let's go with Darth Vader.
It was not Darth Vader.
Anybody else?
- Leia?
- Nope.
- Yoda.
- Dan has it right, it was Yoda.
- Do not underestimate the powers of the Sith.
- That sounds right.
- Or suffer your father's fate, you will.
- Sorry.
- Will we all be doing impressions?
- Before he inverts the sentences.
- I'm not prepared.
- He doesn't invert the sentences much in "Jetfire" at all.
- It's true.
And if you watch these,
so it's just like him doing that to mess with Luke.
- Yeah.
And then later it became, he does it every time.
- All right, Dan, that brings us to you.
Will you get another Star Wars question?
- Likely.
- No, you will not.
- A one, please, Erica.
- All right, it said this is coming from the Walt Disney
Family Edition.
This is from the grownups box.
- Dang it.
- Category, welcome to the world of places.
- I hate places.
- Why are they all in the world?
- They're the worst.
- That's just the world.
- It is.
What, fittingly enough, is the monetary unit of Zaire?
- Fittingly enough, it's the monetary unit of Zaire,
a country that I believe is no longer called Zaire, right?
- I don't know, Stephen?
- I cannot divulge that information.
- Is it the Zaire dollar?
- You should have stopped after the word.
- Zire. - Zire, yep.
- I thought about it and I was like, that seems dumb.
- Well.
- All right, well, it was close.
- We are off to a great start in person here.
So far we have a sweep, a sweep of zeros.
So Jason, can you change that for us?
- Seems unlikely, but I'll give it a try.
A one.
- All right, this is coming from the Doctor Who edition.
I believe this is the 2018 edition
that goes through the first season of Jodie Whittaker.
Category one is Time Lords.
What villain does Clara Oswald follow
into the doctor's own time stream
in his tomb on Trenzalore?
- That is the great intelligence.
- It is, we have our first point.
- Score.
- As played by our good friend,
oh, what's his name?
You got this.
- No points. - It's not for any points.
- But it's a, it's a, it's a, no, it's not.
- He's iconic.
- I know, but now I can't remember his name.
- He was in "Loki", he was in "Star Wars"
later after this. - I know.
- Richard E. Grant. - There we go.
- Richard E. Grant as the great intelligence.
- Oh, from "Husky Hawk".
- He had another dumb name,
but he was revealed to be the great intelligence.
Okay.
Six.
- All right, this is coming from the totally 80s edition.
And I realized looking at the boxes on my shelf
the other day that the Totally 80s Edition
is yet another only sold in Canada version
that has, I think, 500 questions, specifically Canadian.
Let's see if this is one of them.
- Only Canada experienced the 80s.
- Category six is wildcard.
So what Screech Owl author co-wrote the 1989 book
Home Game, colon, Hockey and Life in Canada?
Screech Owl is italicized.
- I think Steve is about to have a seizure.
- Home game hockey in life in Canada is also italicized.
I'm guessing this is one of the 500 Canadian questions.
- Could it be a Canadian hockey player?
I'm just kidding.
(laughing)
- Well, we know it's the author of Screech Owl.
- And that's why it's clearly TV screech Dustin Diamond.
(laughing)
- That was also my first thought.
- Twist. - I admit it.
No, that is not correct.
Steven, did you know this one?
- No, no, I didn't know.
- Wait, what?
- Yeah.
- Somebody named Roy MacGregor?
I know, I know Aurora McGregor.
But I don't, I didn't know that book.
I think I misheard the question and thought it was something else.
Is that like Conor McGregor's grandpa or something?
Uh, yes.
Isn't that the fighter, the MMA fighter?
Is that what we're talking about?
Yeah, I don't know.
Okay.
Mr. McGregor's, uh, Peter Rabbit's, uh, grandson?
That's right.
I'm not speaking about hockey players.
Did you say Mr. McGregor is Peter Rabbit's grandson?
No, because that's a twist on a good movie.
How do you feel about Skeletor and He-Man?
- And my bookmarks.
- Somehow my bookmarks on my document are gone.
So I can't scroll down easily.
- Dan, Skeletor is his enemy.
- And his uncle.
- Yeah, and his uncle.
- Real twisty.
- There's no such thing as a Skeletor free podcast.
- It's true. It's true.
All right. Well, we have one point on the board.
Shelly, can you get us another one?
- I don't know, Erica.
We'll find out.
I got a two.
- All right.
This is coming from the 2000s edition
in which the cards are all different colors.
Each color indicates a category.
This is the pinkish, purplish one.
I don't know what that means,
and I couldn't scroll down to it fast enough.
This is harder than I thought it was gonna be.
One second here while I find it.
Because knowing the category will make a huge difference
in whether I get it right.
- My second category was,
we gave up and there aren't any categories anymore.
I just wanna point out.
- That's true.
This is entertainment, it's a pink card.
- That makes sense.
- You also have a subcategory.
The subcategory of the card is short and sweet.
So keep that in mind as you answer this question.
- Okay.
- What quick-witted son of Christie
on the TV series "Mom" is played by Blake Garrett Rosenthal?
Mom is in italics.
Christie is spelled C-H-R-I-S-T-Y.
- I don't know any of those words you spoke to me.
We want the character, not the act,
you've told me the actor, so we want the character.
- Yeah, well, yes, the character's name.
And you'll need the first name.
- Oh, well, that makes it so much easier.
- Do you know any first names, Shelley?
Just start naming them.
- I should say Dan just for that, but I will not.
I'm gonna say Elliot.
That seems like a good TV character name.
I don't know.
- No, somebody named Roscoe.
- Roscoe is also a good TV character.
- Yes, I agree.
All right.
- After the first round, Jason has won.
(all laughing)
- Not won the game.
- Never, never.
Steven determines.
- Yeah.
- I mean, if nobody scores any points
for the rest of the game, then technically, yes.
- That is how it will work.
No, it is back around to Monty.
- We played for hours,
but Jason actually won after 10 minutes.
- I rolled a two.
- All right, this is coming
from the Walt Disney Family Edition.
It is from the Grown-Us box.
Category two is, "Monty, welcome to the world of music."
It's one of the better worlds.
What key is "We Are The World" written in?
(laughing)
- Wow.
♪ There is a time ♪
- Yeah.
♪ When we must heed a certain call ♪
♪ And the world must come together as one ♪
- Where are my harmonies?
- And now I must stop this for copyright reasons.
We should no longer sing the rest of "We Are The World."
- All right, I'm gonna say G major.
- That is not it.
Steven, you have perfect pitch, do you know this?
I'm gonna hum it in my head and then guess.
(humming)
C major was my guess.
This, everybody, is your scorekeeper, humming.
We are the world.
That's the lamest key.
It's the best key, it's E.
E?
It just says E, not E major or E minor?
I object.
Your objection is noted.
To the record, an overrule.
Welcome back to Random Pursuit, Monty.
(all laughing)
- All right, Lauren, which roll to four?
- All right, this is coming from the 1980s edition.
Yes, it's only shiny on one side of the card,
but I'm not showing you the card right now because--
- They saved money on that.
- Yes. - There was a whole
coding process they didn't have to do.
- Not the totally 80s edition, just the regular 80s edition?
- Just the regular bad 80s edition.
- But more importantly, the quality and style of the card
has come up and that's an important aspect
of random pursuit. - Yeah, I'm always here
for card talk by Erica,
editorializing about production guys.
- After my experience with the good edition of the 80s,
I am skeptical.
- All right, well, category four is TL,
which I think stands for timeline.
- Or time.
- Usually I have all of these in front of me.
- Too long.
- Timeline?
- I could be wrong.
- A category called timeline?
- It's just history with another name.
- No, I was wrong.
- You met a decade-
- It's the world.
- Welcome to the world of times.
- Ooh.
- No, I had it mixed up with lives and times,
which is a totally different game, a different edition.
- No, it stands for total lines.
- This is so much better.
The TL stands for that's life.
(all laughing)
So please enjoy your question about life, I guess.
What does the I stand for
in Minolta's smart Maxome 7000i camera?
And they're asking about the I, it's a lowercase I,
and Maxome is spelled M-A-X-X-U-M.
It's italicized, and then there's the 7000,
seven, zero, zero, zero, and a lowercase I.
So what does that I stand for
in Minolta's smart Maxim 7000i camera?
The only thing I can think of is ISO,
but presumably that's its own acronym.
So that's probably not right.
Intelligent.
- It's a good guess.
- I'm gonna give it to you 'cause it's intelligence.
- Oh, hooray! - Good job.
- The snells are on the board, the rest of us suck.
That's right, so you get to roll again.
$7,000, too much for our cameras.
But it sees so well.
It's a biblically accurate camera.
I rolled a one.
All right.
This is coming from the 20th anniversary edition, no longer
my least favorite edition.
Category one is global view.
Did it get better?
No.
Something worse arrived.
Publish the rankings.
Ooh, that would be fun.
Global view is your category.
What California city was described by columnist Jim
Murray as quote, under policed and over sexed.
- So many.
- California, does that narrow it down?
- San Francisco?
- It's not.
- Los Angeles?
- It is Los Angeles.
- Jim Murray was a sports columnist at the LA Times.
- Oh, he was, that's right.
- I would have guessed San Francisco.
- You had background information that I did not have.
- I would have guessed Oakland.
- People like insulting Oakland.
- Yes, they do.
- That's true.
- There's no there there.
- But you got on the board, so those are good terms.
- I got on the board, that was my goal
for this entire game.
- Lauren has won.
(all laughing)
- Five, please, Erika.
- All right, this is coming from
the Trivial Pursuit Millennium Edition.
Remember, not millennial, millennium.
Category five is sports and leisure.
- Move on.
- Who became the first NFL quarterback
to pass for 50,000 career yards in 1996?
-Steven's posture just changed.
I feel like he knows this one.
-In 1996, I could name some quarterbacks.
I don't know if I, yeah.
I'm just going to go with the one that is the one that I obviously
sometimes get mistaken for, Dan Marino.
-You got it.
-It's Dan Marino.
-It is totally Dan Marino.
Good job.
-Wow.
-When I try to search sometimes, it's like, "Did you mean Dan Marino?"
There you go.
I wrote a one please.
All right, this is coming from genus three.
Category one is people in places.
How old was Drew Barrymore when she began drinking?
You were there, you remember?
Yeah, I remember back at a party, me and Drew.
I feel really uncomfortable.
I'm guessing that answer is way younger than it should be.
How young, how young is too young?
How young is disturbingly young?
Let's say nine.
- You were so close.
- Is it 10?
- It was eight.
- Oh, I was at seven and then I went off.
I think it was on the set of "Firestarter."
- Wow.
- Dang, Joe.
- So picture her there.
(all laughing)
- All right, well, you're on the board.
You're on the board, yes, congratulations.
- Dan Morin has won.
(all laughing)
- All right, go ahead, Jason.
- I'm so used to being told to play,
but we are all just in order here.
- Actually, it's actually Czechs trivia time.
I just realized I forgot to make Monty roll a D8
the first time, but now we're taking advantage
of all eight questions on the card.
- Number four.
- All right.
- So not really.
(laughing)
- No.
All right, this is from Czechs music trivia.
The fourth question is,
what well-known slogan was associated with Sammy K?
That's K-A-Y-E, Sammy K.
It's a well-known slogan, Jason.
- I can't believe you don't know this.
Sammy K. I mean, who among us remembers Sammy K?
- Nobody's raising their hands.
- Nope.
- I'm gonna say,
Rock Around the Clock.
- I mean, you're coming to the right neighborhood.
It's a swing and sway with Sammy K.
- Of course it is.
- Tip of my tongue.
- Big, big band guys.
So a little before Rock Around the Clock.
- Ah, big band.
- Oh, okay.
All right, Shelly, it is now your turn.
- I still have one.
You got it.
- Yeah, Jason still has one.
- No.
- Five.
- All right, a five for Shelly.
- I should tell the microphones, hello, I'm alive.
- All right, this is coming from the DVD
Pop Culture Edition.
Category five is Buzz.
Whatever.
- It's about bees, it's all about bees.
- It's all about bees.
- What member of the British Royal Family
is the author of the Budgie the, sorry,
of the "Budgie the Little Helicopter" children's books.
It's a whole series apparently.
So we need a member of the British royal family.
- I know about them.
British royal family.
I'm just gonna guess princess somebody.
No, I'm gonna guess princess Anne.
- It was Sarah Ferguson.
- Oh, Fergie.
- That was my guess.
I was like, please don't let it be Prince Andrew.
(all laughing)
Real bad.
- Luckily it was not.
All right, Stephen, how do we stand?
- Some of you have won.
The rest of you have not.
(all laughing)
- That into the table has won.
- All right, yeah, the people who are closer to me have not.
I feel a little sad for them.
All right, Monty, what'd you roll?
- I rolled a five.
- All right, this is coming from Trivial Pursuit,
Genus 4, category 5 is sports and leisure.
What golfer bid a tearful farewell to fans
after playing his last US Open in 1994?
- Lee Trevino.
- It was not, it was Arnold Palmer.
- All right, well, that means I was,
Link Trovino probably stopped around then.
They were contemporaries.
- I have no idea about any of these things.
So sure, yeah, good job.
- I rolled a three.
- All right, ooh, this is coming from the Decades edition,
which I think is my newest edition,
which has no even letters on here
to tell me what these categories might be.
So this is dropping in my rankings.
I will tell you that right now.
Category three is news alert.
- Gosh.
- Yeah.
(mimics alarm)
- Not to be confused with fuzz.
- That's life.
- What island country was the starting point
for Diana Nyad's historic 103 mile swim,
which ended on the shores of Key West in 2013?
How far?
Island country, and it was 103 miles.
So 103 miles away from Key West, you will find.
Okay, Cuba's not that far.
Cuba's only like 26 miles from Florida,
but that's literally all the geography
I know about that region.
What's further than that?
I have Island Nation, the island, the country?
- Yeah, you were looking for the island country.
- Oh, both. - That's the way it says.
- Bahamas.
- It is actually Cuba.
- Cuba.
- It is not.
- Key West is very far from Florida.
- Yeah, I think Key West must be so far south.
- They always say Cuba is 90 miles from Florida,
Key West is further.
- Yes, and apparently this is one of the newer cards
that tells you a little extra information.
It took her 53 hours.
- Okay.
- It's Catalina that is 26 miles from LA.
Cuba is 90 miles from Florida.
- For those that remember their Cuban Missile Crisis trivia.
And for those of us who've been to Cuba,
I imagine I'm the only one who is allowed to go at this table. So yeah.
Oh, you now, welcome to Cuba.
They might not let her back in.
That is not the undisclosed location.
And yeah, if she went to Cuba, the US might not let her back in.
That's true.
Yep.
All right. Next is Dan.
Three, please.
All right. This is coming from the Doctor Who edition.
This is the 2018 edition that goes all the way through one season of Jodie Whittaker.
Category episodes and stories.
In the story, the empty child, what spooky phrase did the child and the gas mask repeat over and over?
Are you my mommy?
That one I knew.
You got it. And everybody got to watch me turn the card the correct way, upright,
and then have to flip it over because it goes side to side.
I appreciate that you even check the answers on the Doctor Who card.
I mean, sometimes they're wrong.
Right. You have to get the wrong answer though.
Let's hope that doesn't happen. I don't want to have to think that hard about it.
it is. That's a three. What category was that? That was also a three so you get to choose your edition.
Hot dog. Let's go start. I don't have a hot dog edition. Hot dog the movie edition. But I do have Star Wars. Oh and guess what?
It's another one with a picture on the back. I'm gonna pass this around. Keep your
face down. Yes. No cheating. I'm watching you. I'm not cheating. Tell us what the picture is.
- This is a picture of Coruscant, I believe,
at the end of Return of the Jedi.
It's one of the--
- Special edition. - Special edition.
- Thank you for the clarification.
- Yes. - Yes.
I mean, this edition did come with a very small package
of cards that are about the prequels.
- I had that edition, yeah.
- Those are not included in my deck.
Maybe I will add them,
but right now they're just like underneath the thing.
- If you need more cards, you know.
- Right, I'm running so low.
All right, category three is history.
Remember, this is the history of the Star Wars world,
not ours.
- You say that like they're different things.
You say that like he knows our world's history
better than Star Wars.
(laughing)
- Touche.
What do people pass over their heads
at the end of Return of the Jedi Special Edition?
- What do they pass over their heads?
- Weird question.
- I have a thought and I'm trying to figure out
how to write the right way to phrase it.
Pass over their head.
What do they, sorry, can we read one more time?
- Sure.
What do people pass over their heads
at the end of "Return of the Jedi" special edition?
"Return of the Jedi" special edition is italicized.
I don't know if that helps. - Thank you, I appreciate that.
Is it a fallen, like parts of a statue of the emperor?
- It is not.
It's a stormtrooper.
- Oh. - Even darker.
- Man, I have not watched the special edition
of any game quite some time.
- The latest special edition passes the guy
who sings "Jedi Rocks" over there.
- Is he singing at the time?
- No, he is dead.
(all laughing)
- Makes it extra special.
- As is right and proper.
All right, Jason.
- Four.
- All right, it's coming from Genus3.
Category four is science and nature.
What does the government label, sorry,
what does the government label you
if you have 10% or less of normal vision?
- Legally blind? - That's it. Roll again.
- As someone who is legally blind, I have never heard that defined in that way, ever.
- It contains less than 10% of the time.
- Four. - All right. That's another four. So you get
to choose. - Was it?
- Yeah. - Oh.
- Yep. That was a... Wait. You did roll four last time, correct? Or did I read the wrong
- I don't remember. - I don't remember either.
- Then yeah, choose your edition.
- Check the audio.
- Disney Kids.
- All right.
- I'm here to win.
- Yeah, just question it.
- Oops.
The Baby Boomer and the Disney Kids questions
have the same color in the background of the card.
- I'm sure you can detect which is which.
- And I, yeah, I think you would probably be very unhappy
if I picked the wrong one.
- We had the Baby Boomer edition at home
and the Silver Screen.
They're both very difficult and I don't like them.
- Jason, welcome to the world of fantasy.
- Okay, all right.
- My favorite of the worlds.
What does the cat do?
- I don't know.
and they're both very difficult and I don't like them.
- Jason, welcome to the world of fantasy.
- Okay, hooray.
- My favorite of the worlds.
What does the caterpillar in "Alice in Wonderland"
sit on, a mushroom or a toadstool?
(all laughing)
- Harder than you thought.
- Okay, okay.
- For a children's- - Respect.
- Multiple choice with only two choices question,
this is actually hard.
I'm going to say toadstool.
- It's a mushroom.
(all laughing)
- I like that Jason and I both got you pick cards
and things we've never really seen.
- I know, that makes it hurt all the more.
- Totes still seem more fantastic.
- I agree.
- I have rolled a three.
- All right, well, this is also coming
from the Disney edition kids box
because that's what was next.
- Mushroom.
- So category three, welcome to the world of people,
possibly the worst of all the world.
(all laughing)
- I agree.
- Publish the rankings.
- Who's running with a speeding ticket
inspired the Mickey Mouse cartoon Traffic Troubles?
- Wait, read that again, please.
- Who's run-in with a speeding ticket
inspired the Mickey Mouse cartoon Traffic Troubles?
- They like ran into the speeding ticket?
- No, run in with, I guess.
Run in.
- They like to make these questions
sort of artful in their phrasing,
but I think it boils down to who got a speeding ticket
and then wrote this cartoon.
- Okay, so Mickey Mouse.
So clearly Disney, not Warner Brothers
that I had in my head for a second there.
traffic troubles.
I don't know, Minnie Mouse.
- I think you were off the track a little bit there.
The answer is actually Walt Disney.
- Oh, I see.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And that was one of the different editions
have different like good basic answers.
If it's the Walt Disney edition
and it's a Disney question and it's a real person,
it's just Walt Disney.
- You did say world of people.
I'm a mountain listing comprehension
is not doing well today.
- All right, after three rounds, goodness me,
Dan and Jason have actual scores of two.
Lauren has one point and Shelley and Monty
still looking to get on the board.
- All right, Monty, this might be your time
because it's junior trivia.
- I'm rolling a die supposedly made from a Civil War bullet.
- Wow.
- It is a one.
- All right, well, it would be cool
if this was a Civil War question, but it's not.
This is coming from junior trivia two.
So think like a 10 to 13 year old from 1983 or four,
somewhere in there.
- Poop.
(laughing)
Nailed it.
- You're on a good start there.
Who is the Duke of Edinburgh married to?
The Duke of Edinburgh married to?
- Duke of Edinburgh.
- Burra, yes.
- In 1984?
- Yep.
- Lady Diana Spencer?
- No.
- The Queen!
- Queen Elizabeth II.
I cannot be bothered to care about the royals at all
in any respect.
- That's why we let you play with us.
- I salute you for that.
All right, Lauren.
- I rolled a one.
- All right, this is coming from the 90s edition.
Your question is coming from 1994.
The cards specify the year.
So category one is oops.
Oh dear.
- That's life.
- Yep.
- Welcome to the world of people.
- What US state's lucky voters got to pull the lever
For Howard Stern for governor.
- Oh.
- What US states, lucky voters,
got to pull the lever for Howard Stern for governor.
I feel like this is editorializing in a weird way.
Did we have a recall election in '94?
New York.
It is New York.
- Oh, roll again.
- Yeah, he's very New York.
- Yes, if that was a Jeopardy question,
- See the way my mind works-- - Lucky would mean something
and you'd have to guess Nevada or New Jersey maybe,
but it's not, it's just trivia per se.
- The way my mind works, I wonder whether
they were actually using lepers in 1994.
- One, I believe again.
- Yes. - I think they were
in New York. - What edition
would you like your question to come from?
- Something easy.
- Well, you know, junior trivia,
one or two are popular choices.
The Disney Kids box is popular,
although that didn't-- - Disney Kids.
- Okay. - Great, let's do it.
- And this time I know just where to find them.
All right, category one, Welcome to the World of Places.
- Yay, we're old. - Love places.
- All right. - I hate them so much.
- Our visitors allowed to walk up the Washington Monument.
Yes.
- No.
- You have to take the elevator.
- No, they do that in.
- You go down, but you have to take the elevator.
- Oh, I've never done that.
I was just thinking about the "Spider-Man" movie
where she doesn't wanna go up.
- Yeah, they might, they might.
I don't think so, 'cause there's only one staircase,
I think is the problem.
Everybody's going down.
- I didn't do it. - Well, that's a world
of places for you.
- Yeah, no.
- Oh, well, I chose poorly.
- It's a rough world.
- Well, all of our special roles have led to failure now.
- That's true.
- This is unusual.
- I also had a 50/50 chance.
- Yes, yeah.
- Well done.
- Five, please.
- All right, this is coming from Junior Trivia One.
- I'll probably botch it.
- All right, number five.
Where is Mount St. Helens volcano?
Where is it?
Remember, five to nine year old.
- We will need the exact longitude
and latitude coordinates for this, by the way.
- Oregon?
- It's Montana.
- No. - Washington.
- It's Washington.
- Okay, I'm told you can see it, right?
- Yeah.
- We're very high from Seattle.
- The river up here is literally,
well, I mean, undisclosed location.
It's very close to where we are.
- We're recording from Mount St. Helens.
- On a plane ride I recently took,
there were people looking out my adjacent window,
pointing and going, "That's Mount St. Helens."
No, it's something else.
There was a lot of argument.
- I was told I could see it,
and the answer is I did not realize there was a line.
- State borders are very tricky.
The card specifically says, "The state of Washington, USA."
- Yeah, I was gonna say,
would the United States have been a good enough answer there?
Six.
- All right, Jason, this is coming from the family edition.
- Right. - Yes.
But this is the, let's see,
the yellow cards are the children's cards.
- Yay, I am doomed.
- What was the number again?
- Six. - Six, all right.
Six, wild card.
- Not a category.
- Welcome to the world of wild cards.
- What bird's holes did one time
Arizona Lieutenant Governor Ernest Hall
collect thousands of as a hobby?
What bird's holes?
- I'm gonna say the woodpecker.
- Yes.
- Any other answer is incredibly disturbing.
- Cloaca would have been my second guess.
- Yes, but which bird's cloacas?
- All right, number six was my last roll,
so now we all remember that.
And it's a one.
- All right, this is coming from the Friends edition,
where the one, category one is at the bottom of the card,
where we have seasons one and two.
- Oh, excellent.
- Yeah, the Friends edition just makes me so mad.
Why would you put seasons one and two
at the bottom of the card?
Who does that?
Anyway, executive decision.
- Could it be any more annoying?
- No.
Also well played, reference acknowledged.
seasons one and two, where does the gang find
Rachel's lost wedding ring?
- Oh man, it hurts more when you know you did know this
and you don't know it anymore.
Rachel's lost wedding ring, 'cause she was in the pilot,
she's fleeing a marriage, is that right, I think?
- I'm not gonna answer that question
in part 'cause I don't remember.
- I think that's how that show starts.
They find it in
Marcel the monkey.
(laughing)
- Not it.
It's in Monica's lasagna.
- Okay.
- Which makes about as much sense.
- They found that the lasagna was later found
in Marcel the monkey.
- Which was inside a raw turkey.
- All right, Shelly.
- That's horrifying.
I rolled a one.
- All right, this is coming from the 1980s edition.
The janky old.
old 1980s edition. "Personalities" I think is the is the category. What ill-fated
Democratic presidential hopeful said of himself? "He educated the people."
Okay this is a topic with which I am somewhat familiar. The answer however, Democratic
presidential hopeful in a edition that was released it's about the 80s it's
about the 80s yes I'm sorry repeat the quote to me again please sure he
educated the people yes well that clarifies it doesn't it yeah so this is
about the 80s you know that's what I said about my favorite teacher in high
school he educated the people welcome to the world I'm just gonna go with Walter
and people it was not it was Duke caucus nope Gary Hart it was Gary Hart
- That is not the Gary Hart quote I would have thought.
(laughing)
- He educated the people about what not to do
as a candidate for sure.
- All right, that's the end of four rounds, kids.
Jason and Dan tied at the top of three.
Lauren was two, Shelly was none,
and Monty hoping to get yet another question,
but the Royal Family also was none.
(laughing)
- I have rolled a five.
- All right, this is coming from the Baby Boomer edition.
Category five is lives and times,
which is what I was confused about earlier.
What couple named their first born child Chastity?
- Sonny and Cher.
- Correct, do you know their last name?
- Sonny Bono and Sherilyn Sarkeesian.
- Oh wow, wow.
- Bonus ghost point for Monty,
the card says Sonny and Cher Bono.
- Chastity is now Chas.
- That's right.
- Now I have rolled a three.
- All right, this is coming from the DVD
pop culture edition category three is music under what name did 60s musical
eccentric Don van Vliet record V-L-I-E-T under what name did 60s
musical eccentric Don van Vliet record? Captain Beefheart. You got it!
Big influence on Frank Zappa real weirdo check him out.
- All right.
- Monty is zooming.
I rolled another three.
- Oh, what edition would you like your question
to come from?
- Genus one, please.
- I thought so.
- The edition Monty has memorized.
- All right, and that was a one, no three, three.
Okay, so history.
Who discovered Victoria Falls?
- Ooh, interesting.
- And colonial.
- Yeah, I was gonna say an asterisk on that one.
- Definitely.
- Yes.
was in, oh boy, I don't know my explorers as much as I should,
nor my geography, so this could be wildly wrong.
Livingstone?
- Yes, indeed. - That's gonna be my guess.
- Do you know his first name?
It's not required. - I don't.
- It's David.
- Oh.
- No, Stanley's the one who meets him.
- Right. - Oh, Stanley meets Livingstone.
That's right, Dr. Livingstone, I presume,
said Mr. Stanley, who does not have a doctorate
in fighting people. - That was a sweep.
Congratulations.
- Well done, Monty. - So far, first sweep.
- On the board.
- I rolled a three.
- All right, this is coming from the Genus 5 edition.
Category three is history.
What US city's Olympic officials were indicted on charges
they gave $1 million in cash and gifts to IOC brass
to secure the 2002 Winter Games?
We're looking for the US city
whose Olympic officials did all those things.
- I think it's Salt Lake City.
- Salt Lake City.
- I'll say this should just stop
from before 2002 Winter Games,
just be like all of them.
- Yeah.
- Only one was indicted though.
- I rolled a three.
- That's another three.
- Oh, that's another three.
What category would you like this question to come from?
- Something better than the last time.
- You did the Disney one last time.
Would you like a junior?
- Yes, I would.
- Okay.
Now, do you want junior trivia one or two?
- One.
- All right.
Last one over there, so.
All right, category three.
There's no categories.
Actually, that's not true.
There are categories.
Listener Sab reminded me that there are categories
for junior trivia,
and I had completely forgotten about that,
and I was going to put them on my spreadsheet,
and I didn't, so we don't know what they are still.
- But there are categories.
- #Teaser for the next episode of "Randor Pursuit"
where I actually update this.
What are the teeth made of on the sharpest saws?
- Diamonds.
- It is diamonds, roll again.
- One.
- All right, this is also coming from Junior Trivia One.
- Okay, what bionic parts did the $6 million man have?
- Oh, geez.
- The family show.
- Okay, she had an ear, so it's not that.
- Wow, they really want all of it.
- Yeah.
- I only watched the girl one.
- 'Cause it was better.
- Yeah, I know.
Arm, how many?
You're not gonna tell me.
Arm and eye and probably a leg.
- I'm gonna give it to you.
It's one arm, one eye and legs.
But this is a ridiculous thing
that they were asking for all of it.
- Arm, eye and legs.
- Because he had to run fast.
He could do it.
(all laughing)
- All right, so that's another sweep.
- Wilders.
All right, no pressure, Dan.
Oh wait, do you have a d8 over there or does somebody need to pass you one? Thank you Monty.
Mm-hmm
One all right very important this is coming from the 50s and 60s edition of Chex trivia
I'm tired of tech heads. What is the name of Elvis Presley's first record?
You just put that movie it wouldn't help okay
- Okay.
Two guesses.
I'm gonna guess, man, I don't know.
I'm gonna guess Elvis.
(laughing)
- That's a very good guess.
That is not the answer.
Does anybody know this?
I certainly did not.
It's called "My Happiness."
- No.
- It's not a single or something too,
not his first album.
- Well, it says record, so it could be an album.
- I think it's the studios and they cut it
and it didn't go anywhere and he got better songwriters
and yeah, it's in the movie.
- Again. - Should've watched it.
- All right, Jason.
- Five.
- All right, this is coming from
the Trivial Pursuit Millennium Edition,
category five is sports and leisure.
How many times did Babe Ruth win baseball's triple crown?
- Come on, how many times?
That is not stuff that I know.
Over 15 seasons, triple crown though,
it's batting average.
- I don't even know what that means.
- There are a lot of guys, you're the leader in the league
in batting average home runs and runs batted in.
- Do you get an actual crown?
'Cause otherwise I do not care.
- You don't.
You just, I mean, you could, you might have.
Batting average, I'm not sure he actually did that well in.
So I'm going to say none.
- The card says zero, but I'm gonna give it to you.
- Yeah. - Nice.
- It's not just batting average.
Luke Gehrig got so many RBIs.
- Well, earlier before Gehrig,
he probably led the league in homers and RBIs,
but I don't think he ever did batting average.
- You get to roll again.
- Okay, what was my number there?
Does anybody remember?
It was one, five, five, four.
- All right, this is coming from the Doctor Who edition,
the second Doctor Who edition.
So you might have some Jodie Whittaker in there.
Category five is, wait, no, what did you roll this time?
- Four. - Four.
- Sorry, five was last time, four.
Years and dates.
What century is it when the pteroleptiles
escape the jails of Raga and become stranded on Earth?
- You've gotta be kidding me.
What century is the pteroleptiles?
I can't even do the pteroleptiles or who are they even?
- I'm not gonna answer that question,
but this time I do know the answer.
- I know, I know, pteroleptiles.
- Can you make a noise like the pteroleptiles?
- Um.
- Stephen probably could.
- No.
(laughing)
- It's the 30th century.
- It is not.
It is the 1600s.
It was the Tereleptiles accidentally started
the fire of London.
- What?
- They also destroyed-
- Demons?
What is that?
- Visitation.
- In the visitation.
- The visitation.
- They also destroyed the fifth doctor's sonic screwdriver.
- Okay.
- Those guys are jerks.
I'm just saying.
- Totally.
- Isn't that good?
Isn't the sonic screwdriver kind of leaned on
pretty heavily?
- That's why the producers were like,
we're getting rid of this thing.
I was like, no, I was a child, it was very sad.
- And then they brought it back.
- I have rolled a six.
- All right, this is also coming from the Doctor Who edition
of the other Doctor Who edition.
Category six is-- - This game is rigged.
- It is? - 100%.
- Cast, crew and beyond.
Which BBC department performed
the original Doctor Who theme tune?
And you have multiple choice.
So it's either the stereophonic workshop,
the radiographic workshop, the radiophonic workshop,
or the symphonic orchestra?
- I'm gonna choose symphonic orchestra
because I hope that's right.
- Last is the radiophonic workshop.
- The radiophonic workshop.
- That's the one I wanna work for
'cause it just sounds fun.
- It does sound cool.
- And they're very nice fellows.
- Yeah, that's a little Dr. Who expert drop there.
- That's true.
- They're very nice.
- Although one of the few women in this course
was at the head of that, Delia Darbyshire, who wrote it.
You're right, she made it happen.
Alright, Lauren has gone out of the hack to skip to the lead with her sweep.
There you go.
She's sliding right in there.
There's a whole bunch of curling metaphors.
She's got five, Jason has four, Dan and Monty with his own sweep have three, and Shelley
with none.
But it's still not early at all.
It's still not over.
We are now entering the last regular round of Random Pursuit here, where the round after
this will be infinite.
has judged us.
Dumb wanting.
I have rolled a one.
- All right, this is coming from
the Trivial Pursuit Millennium Edition.
Category one, people and places.
How many years does a governor's term last
in New Hampshire and Vermont?
- I don't think anybody can be governor
of New Hampshire and Vermont.
(all laughing)
Seems illegal.
Two years.
- You are correct, roll again.
- Wow.
- Two.
- All right, this is coming from my second newest edition.
It's the Dungeons and Dragons edition,
which I apparently neglected to put on here.
So I don't know what the category is at all.
- Oh, dragons.
- Is there a letter?
- No, there's a little picture.
It looks like it might be spells or something.
Can you look it up for me?
- Spells or something.
- What was your number again?
- Two.
- Okay.
It's a book with a 20-sided die hovering over it.
- Rules.
- I think it might be history,
like real world history of Dungeons & Dragons.
- Oh, please, please, please, please, please.
(laughing)
But not history in Dungeons & Dragons.
- There we go.
Dungeons & Adventures, what is it, number?
- Two.
- Two, it is Monsters.
- This does not look like Monsters.
I think that is incorrect.
- No, that doesn't compute.
- Oh, well, it's the official trivia.
- It's wrong.
- It's the right page, so.
- All right, well, anyway, it's yellow.
Monty, this is your yellow question
about Dungeons and Dragons.
What lead designer of third edition D&D
was known for his previous work on smaller press RPGs
like Ars Magica?
- Oh, somebody who worked on Ars Magica
and third edition D&D?
- Mm-hmm, yep.
- Oh boy, this is going to kill me when I get it wrong.
- Unless you get it right.
I, I, oh boy.
Third edition.
I'm just gonna say Lisa Stevens.
- It is not that, it is Jonathan Tweet.
Yes, at least you knew the name.
- Yeah, of course it's Jonathan Tweet.
- All right, that brings us-- - He's a good man.
- I know him.
- Check that, more name drops.
- I rolled a six.
All right, this is coming from the Star Trek
50th anniversary edition.
- That's right, not 50th. - Top 50th.
- 50, and this is coming from "Star Trek III,"
the search for Spock.
- Oh, I've only seen that once.
- Well, will that be enough to help?
You need to know ships, that is your category is ships.
- Who are they searching for and searching for?
- Who sabotaged the Excelsior's engine
so it could not pursue the Enterprise?
Who sabotaged?
- I literally don't have anything.
- Guess a Star Trek character.
- But a bad one, right?
- Or is this a good thing? - I'll read it again.
I'll read it again.
Who sabotaged the Excelsior's engine
so it could not pursue the Enterprise?
- So a good person.
I mean, I'm not making any judgments here.
- No judgment, but presumably Scotty.
- It was Scotty.
- Oh, nice. - In the David Gerrold book,
he says, "Scotty has stolen their spark plugs."
I've always remembered that.
(laughing)
- This also gives us a little extra information.
Scotty, who said, "The more they overthink the plumbing,
the easier it is to stop up the drain."
So not spark plugs, apparently, but.
- Yeah, why is there a drain connected to your engines?
Bad move.
- I rolled a one.
All right, this is coming from the Globetrotter edition,
which was sent by-
- All questions about the Harlem Globetrotters.
- This is gonna go to us as well.
These are the cards that Anthony Johnston mailed to me.
This is a question about North America.
"Which movie hears Gene Wilder say
These are the people of the land,
the common clay of the new west, you know, morons.
- Oh, he was in a Mel Brooks movie.
- More than one.
- It's true, he was in several.
- This is where my memory is not great.
I'm looking across and you're nodding at me.
- Read it from our minds.
- It's not coming out.
- Look at Jason's eyes.
The scene is playing in his head right now.
(laughing)
- It's not helping.
No, I can think of Willy Wonka and it's not that.
- That would be a weird scene in Willy Wonka.
- Yeah, not like all the other ones.
- He was talking about the usual loopers, gross.
(laughing)
- I think he was in the Frankenstein one,
but it's probably not that.
And this, it doesn't help.
And I'm not gonna Liz this out.
I'm not.
- I mean, you did it with Scotty.
- That was better.
No, I feel like there's a Mel Brooks movie
where they all sit around the campfire and fart.
And I think that's it, but I don't know what it is.
The Wild Wild West.
- When we're playing Jeopardy at home,
that is counted as a correct answer.
- Ah, this is not Jeopardy at home.
- And it's blazing sadly.
- You are not at home right now.
- That was the correct movie, but yes, I needed the title.
- Well, in my heart, I got that right.
- Ghost points. - Ghost points.
- Ghost points, yeah.
- All right, that brings us to Dan.
- I need some catching up to do in this round.
Four, please.
- All right, this is coming from GenusFive.
Category four is science and nature.
What computer company went warm and fuzzy
with ads featuring some of its 307,500 employees?
A computer company went warm and fuzzy
with ads featuring some of its 307,500 employees.
And I can tell you that this edition of Trivial Pursuit
came out in 2000.
So it would have been before 2000.
- So not Facebook.
- Warm and fuzzy feels like a toss up.
I don't know why, but I'm thinking Intel.
- I'm afraid not. - IBM?
- It was IBM.
- Yeah, without any employees, it's gotta be IBM.
- Yeah, and they went warm and fuzzy
because they're normally all corporate.
- Incorporate, yeah.
- And West Valley was never pictured
because apparently it was not warm and fuzzy.
- But for some reason I had something in my head
that Intel had a, it had like bunnies or something.
- Well, yeah, it was the bunny suits with the little--
- With the ears and stuff, right?
- But they were still in their little getups.
- Yeah, I don't know, that's why I was thinking that,
but overthought it.
- 300,000 people.
- Yeah, 300,000 people.
- Not anymore.
- No, five.
- All right, this is coming from Genus One,
in which category five is science and nature.
- Nature, yes.
- What's the largest gland in the human body?
- I feel like we actually just did this one on a podcast.
The largest gland in the human body is the...
(laughing)
If it makes that sound, it's broken.
- Oh, so many glands.
- Welcome to the world of glands.
- All right, that's my new least favorite word.
- Glands, the thyroid.
- It is not, it's the liver.
- Oh yeah, see, I think I did this
and it was a trick question because it's an organ.
- Yeah, the thyroid's like the second though, I think.
- Yeah.
- The liver is not a gland.
- I rolled a five.
- All right, this is coming from the Star Wars edition.
This is another one with a picture on the back.
I'm going to pass you this card.
- So many pictures.
- Yup, I don't know if it will help at all.
So far they have not been helpful.
- I don't know Star Wars.
- These guys with lightsabers.
- Yeah, it's two people with lightsabers.
- They have lightsabers.
- They seem upset with each other.
- They're causing so much.
- They're usually not big fans of their people.
- All right, category five is droids, creatures and aliens.
Who was separated from Luke Skywalker
during the search through Cloud City?
Leia? I don't know.
- It is not Leia.
- Beep, beep, beep, beep, beep, beep, beep, beep.
- You did say droids, you did not.
- But it's creatures and aliens,
and they're all aliens.
But yes, it was R2-D2.
- R2-D2.
- R2-D2 is not the number, I don't know,
I'm trying to make a reference between two,
but nobody has two.
- Segway abandoned.
- Segway abandoned, abort, abort.
Lauren leads, heading into the final round of this with six.
Jason and Monty are tied at four,
- Dan a three, Shelly with none.
- It is worse to be last when you know answers
to other people's questions.
It's terrible.
- That's random pursuit.
- It is.
All right, we're gonna start with Lauren.
And she's going to set the benchmark for everybody else.
- I rolled a four.
- All right, this is coming from Trivial Pursuit Volume Six.
That's right, not Gina Six, Volume Six.
Category four, Science and Nature.
What ingredient in microwave popcorn is being investigated
for causing a rare factory worker's disease
called popcorn packer's lung.
And the being investigated was in 2003.
- Strange present tense for a trivial pursuit question.
- Uh-huh.
- Those investigations take a lot.
- Well, it's the seventh edition.
They assume you're just getting the new one every year.
- In the eighth edition, they had like,
oh, it's all wrapped up.
(all laughing)
- And they went on to ask a mysterious question.
- Just wanted to let you know they looked into this.
- Yeah, so what ingredient in microwave popcorn
is being investigated for causing a rare factory workers
disease called popcorn packers lung.
It's probably not the popcorn.
- Yeah, that'd be awful.
I don't know.
- Probably a short investigation.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, they open up a lung.
(all laughing)
I don't know.
So I guess it's gonna be a quick out on the next one.
You won't have to get very many points to get any aspartame.
It's the artificial butter apparently.
Artificial butter.
- Yeah, there's only popcorn butter and salt.
- Salt.
- Salt long.
- All right, so that brings us around to Shelly.
Shelly, oh, actually you need an eight sided die.
Can somebody pass one to her?
- Well, we have all the things we need
- We're in the, I like rolling each side of the die.
- Chex TV.
- And we have
a
- Eight.
- An eight.
- All right, this is coming from the Chex TV trivia.
Who was the voice of Harry Boyle on
Wait 'Til Your Father Gets Home?
We wanna know who is the voice of Harry Boyle
on Wait 'Til Your Father Gets Home.
- Do we have a date range on Chex trivia?
- Chex trivia came out in 1984.
So sometime before 1984.
- There was that right, yeah.
And I'm sorry, the category was.
- There's no categories,
it's just a bunch of random weird questions.
- So we don't know whether this is a TV series or a--
- Oh yeah, TV, sorry, it's TV trivia.
Yes, sorry.
- Harry Boyle, "Wait 'Til Your Father Gets Home."
- Thousands and thousands of years of TV trivia.
(all laughing)
- Who is the voice of Harry Boyle
on "Wait 'Til Your Father Gets Home?"
- Wait 'Til Your Father, God.
- It's in quotation marks, but they have no--
- Oh, there you go, that changes everything.
- They have no italics on these cards,
so I'm assuming that was the TV show.
- Couldn't afford that font with the italics.
- I think they couldn't. - Not a show I know,
so perhaps it is Canadian or of another country,
or I'm just, anyways.
I'm going to have to make some sort of uneducated guess.
Here it comes.
Coming right now, yep.
(laughing)
- Daws Butler, I don't know.
- Good guess, it was a cartoon.
- Well, they said voice, I assume.
Unless it was like someone never seen or something.
- Right, right, yeah.
At least it's a name I recognize,
but I did not know this, Tom Bosley.
- Oh, okay. - That makes sense.
- It does.
- It was that real-- - Happy days, right?
- Yep, yeah.
It was a family cartoon.
The mother talked exactly like the mother on Family Guy.
- All right, so Dan, you are next.
- Does Dan have four?
- No, Dan has three.
- Okay.
- I think you and Jason are tied with four.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
(dice clatters)
- Three, please.
- All right, this is coming from the Silver Screen Edition.
Category three is off-screen.
(all laughing)
- Wait.
- It's immediately about category three.
- Behind the silver screen.
Just right away in category three.
What did We Magazine call, quote,
"A symbol of totally irrelevant accomplishment."
- Oui is italicized and it is French as the O-U-I.
- Oh. - Oui, yep.
So what did Oui magazine call, quote,
"A symbol of totally irrelevant accomplishment."
(exhaling)
- Do we end the silver screen,
does it cover a specific era?
Is there some?
- It's about movies, so it's anything
before the silver screen edition was published,
and that was in 1983.
So any movie type stuff off screen,
'cause that's your category,
before 1983, totally irrelevant accomplishment.
- I'm gonna say the Oscars.
- Also known as?
- Academy Awards.
- Correct.
- Okay, it's the French, they seem snooty.
We magazine was not French, it was a,
it was a boob magazine from the 70s.
(laughing)
- My point stands.
- All right.
- I thought about the golden gloves
because it's like, that seems too early.
Also a three.
Does that apply to anything in this round?
Yeah, you get to choose the edition your question comes from.
Well, it tanked me last time. I'm going to Star Wars again.
Alright.
One moment while I pull out a Star Wars card.
Oh, there we go.
Last one. Pass it around. It's got another picture on it.
Woohoo! So many pictures.
Please describe what you see on that card for the audience.
Well, this is a controversial card.
Oh!
This is Han Solo and Greedo seated in the cantina.
- Oh boy. - There's some smoke rising.
- Somebody has shot. - Somebody shot someone else,
but who?
- And in what order? - Yeah, most importantly.
- Okay, and that was category three, which is history.
What did Grito say he'd been looking forward to
for a long time?
- Okay.
(all laughing)
- Oh boy.
- And if you can answer in Rhodian, please.
- Una gota solo.
Um...
- What did Greedo say he'd look forward to?
- Okay, technically the line is like,
I've been looking forward to this for a long time.
- Uh-huh.
- Do we need something more specific?
- Yeah, it's asking for something more specific.
I mean, Steven's like, I don't like this question.
- Objection, that's inference.
- What do you infer?
- This could be so many things.
catching Han Solo, shooting Han Solo, killing Han Solo,
turning him into Jabba the Hutt for the bounty,
one of those.
- Yes. - But which one?
- Yeah. - I mean,
because it's not actually in the movie
and you said it specifically. - Catching Han Solo.
- Yeah.
- Killing Han Solo. - Killing Han Solo.
- Yes, that's a terrible, terrible question.
- It is a bad question because there's no predicate.
- Yeah, it just says this.
- Yeah, the answer should be this.
- Yeah. - It really should be.
- Sitting in a booth at a cantina with Han Solo.
- Clearly. - If you said,
- I've been looking forward to killing you for a long time.
No wonder Han shot him.
- Yeah.
(laughing)
- Yeah, like we've said before,
the genre editions are the hardest and the worst.
- All right, we're still going, all right.
- Yeah, I bet you have six.
- Efforts acknowledged.
- All right, this is coming from
the Dungeons and Dragons edition,
in which category six is something purple.
- Yeah, something purple, something new.
- Yep.
Which of the outer planes is a morass
of impermanent matter and energy with no structure,
but what can be imposed by disciplined minds?
Which of the outer planes?
And I have to turn this freaking card over sideways.
- I'm gonna guess the astral plane.
- It is not the astral plane, I am sorry.
- Is it the plane of chaos?
- It is not the plane of chaos.
Anyone else?
- It's not the material plane, it's not the negative.
- I think they changed it a couple of times
in multiple editions.
- Yeah, I don't know what the outer planes.
- Astral and ethereal planes can't be outer planes
'cause they're right here.
- Frontier Airlines.
(laughing)
- The world of planes. - Too soon, Jason, too soon.
- Welcome to the world of planes.
- It is Limbo, also known as the ever-changing chaos
of Limbo, so chaos maybe, but I don't, I don't.
- Limbo to its friends.
- Yes, mm-hmm.
- Okay. - So.
- There's only one rule in Limbo, it's how low can you go?
- Exactly.
- All right.
- Both Monty and Jason have four,
so how do you want to do this?
- Roll off, dance off, then roll off.
- Well, we'll go off, we'll go in order of players.
I go, Monty goes first, yeah.
- What is my target?
- Your target, so the target now,
with only two contestants to go,
Lauren has six and currently with the lead.
Dan ended with five.
Jason and Monty with four.
Shelly is sadly out with zero.
So there you go. - Okay.
- So you only have to get three right to take the lead,
but then you have to worry about Jason coming up from behind.
- All right.
Two.
- All right, this is coming from the 90s edition,
1996 specifically.
Category two is wired.
What computer company created a removable disk drive
that could read and write 3.5 inch floppies
as well as its own 120 megabyte super disks?
And that's all one word, capital S,
capital D for super disks.
What computer company?
Okay, I'm torn between Zip and Jazz, spelled J-A-Z.
I'm gonna say Zip.
- It is neither of those.
- Neither of those are a company.
- Oh, they're made by Iomega.
- Nope.
- No, 'cause that is--
- No, but it's a super drive.
- The Zip drive didn't read--
- It didn't read floppy drives 'cause I had one.
Was it LaCie?
- Nope. - Nope.
- Nope.
- This is fun.
- Yeah. - This is fun.
(laughing)
- Gateway 2000?
- Toshiba. - Dell?
- Gateway 2000 in 1996, Jason, come on.
- 1982, right?
- Uh, it's gotta be a storage company
of some kind.
- That's a good point.
- I'm gonna put you out of, nope, mm-mm.
Compaq.
- Compaq!
- And it saved the company
and made them what they are today.
- But they didn't have warm and fuzzy employees
to put in commercials.
- All right, so that brings us to Jason.
- This is the last chance.
- This is going down to the snails, isn't it?
- One.
- All right, it's coming from the 1980s edition,
the lousy only shiny on one side edition.
That's the official title.
- Yes.
Category personalities.
- Poisonalities.
- What's George Bush's full name?
- George Herbert Walker Bush?
- It is.
- Which George Bush?
- This is the 1980s edition.
- He still existed.
Prove it.
- But no one cares.
- Touche.
- Two.
- All right, this is coming from the 1960s edition.
Category two is--
- What is George Bush's full name?
(laughing)
- No, 'cause it's entertainment.
- What is Ronald Reagan's birth name?
What was a 1928 Porter automobile better known as on TV in 1966?
[LAUGHTER]
What?
What was a 1928 Porter automobile better known as on TV in 1966?
The Batmobile?
I know.
Car 54, where are you?
Let Shelly answer.
My Mother the Car.
It was, which had a great theme song.
It was on my list.
It would have been my third guess.
Now she is my mother dear.
- My other ear is in the way.
- Are we interested with some interesting scores there,
Steven, huh?
- Very interesting.
Well, Shelly finishes zero,
but we were very happy to have you here, Shelly, in person.
- Thanks so much.
- Monty with a nice late surge finishes four.
Jason and Dan tied with five,
but the winner in our first ever appearance
on Random Pursuit is Lauren Snow with six.
(cheering)
- And she gets to be known as that,
or no, no, I should say clearly, clarification here,
She has the right to brag about that
until we play together again.
- Yeah.
- This is absolutely correct.
Thank you everybody.
- I would encourage you to exercise that right.
- Thank you everybody for joining me around this table.
I wanna thank all of our players,
Monty, Lauren, Dan, Jason, and Shelly.
Special thanks to my scorekeeper, spouse,
and person who drove me to this undisclosed location,
Steven Schepanski.
And thank you as always to our listeners.
Please join us again on the next Incomparable Game Show.
Be seeing you.
(upbeat music)